Lewis Nathaniel Chase Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Lewis Nathaniel Chase Papers 1836-1947 (bulk 1900-1941)
MSS15602
Chase, Lewis Nathaniel, 1873-1937
89,000 items
224 containers
89.6 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Editor, author, and educator. Autographed letters and correspondence with poets, writers, artists, musicians, and actors; family papers; and miscellaneous personal and academic material stemming from Chase's career as a writer and university professor.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Aiken, Conrad, 1889-1973--Correspondence.; Chase family.; Chase, Emma Lester, 1885- Emma Lester Chase papers.; Chase, Lewis Nathaniel, 1873-1937.; Chase, Pearl-Adell, 1872-1955. Pearl-Adell Chase papers.; De la Mare, Walter, 1873-1956--Correspondence.; Frost, Robert, 1874-1963--Correspondence.; Hardy, Thomas, 1840-1928--Correspondence.; Housman, A. E. (Alfred Edward), 1859-1936--Correspondence.; Masters, Edgar Lee, 1868-1950--Correspondence.; Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1892-1950--Correspondence.; Robinson, Edwin Arlington, 1869-1935--Correspondence.
Subjects
Actors--Correspondence.; American literature.; Americans--China.; Americans--India.; Artists--Correspondence.; Authors, American--Correspondence.; Authors, English--Correspondence.; English literature.; Literature--Study and teaching--China.; Literature--Study and teaching--India.; Literature--Study and teaching--United States.; Literature.; Musicians--Correspondence.; Poetry.
Occupations
Authors.; Editors.; Educators.
Provenance
The papers of Lewis Nathaniel Chase, editor, author, and educator, were given to the Library of Congress by Emma Lester Chase in 1951.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Lewis Nathaniel Chase are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1873, June 27 Born, Sidney, Maine
1895 A.B., Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
1898 M.A., Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
1903 Ph.D., Columbia University, New York, N.Y. Published The English Heroic Play. New York: Columbia University Press, Macmillan Co., agents
1902 1916 Taught English literature at various universities, including Columbia University, New York, N.Y.; University of Indiana, Bloomington, Indiana; University of Louisville, Louisville, Ky.; and University of Bordeaux, Bordeaux, France
1910 Published Bernard Shaw in France. Bordeaux: Imprimerie nouvelle F. Fech & cie.
1913 Published Poe and His Poetry. London: G. G. Harrap & Co.
1916 1917 Instructor, University of Wisconsin, Madison, Wis.
1917 1919 Acting assistant professor, University of Rochester, Rochester, NY
1919 1922 Professor of English studies, Aligarh Muslim University, Aligarh, Uttar Pradesh, India
1921 1925 Taught English at Yenching Peking National University, Peking, China, and Peking Normal University, Peking, China
1925 1927 Lecturer, University of California, Southern Branch, Los Angeles, Calif., and California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, Calif.
1927 1929 Taught at Union College, Schenectady, NY
1929 1931 English professor, Duke University, Durham, N.C.
1931 1933 English professor, Brown University, Providence, R.I.
1937 Died
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Lewis Nathaniel Chase (1873-1937) span the years 1836-1947, with the bulk of the material between 1900 and 1941. The collection consists of correspondence, writings, biographical matter, student papers, printed material, and miscellany relating to Chase's career as an editor, author, and English professor in various universities in the United States and abroad, including India and China. Featured is editorial correspondence with thousands of American and English authors of his period, including most notably Conrad Aiken, Walter De la Mare, Robert Frost, Thomas Hardy, A. E. Housman, Edgar Lee Masters, Edna St. Vincent Millay, and Edward Arlington Robinson. Additionally there is his correspondence with artists, musicians, and actors, as well as his lecture notes, literary manuscripts, family letters, diaries and scrapbooks. Also in the collection is correspondence, diaries, writings, poetry, notes, and other papers of Chase's first wife, Pearl-Adell Chase; his second wife, Emma Lester Chase; and other family members.
The collection is in the folders and order in which it was received but is organized into eight series: Correspondence with Poets; Correspondence with Authors, Artists, Musicians, and Actors; General File; Family Correspondence; Miscellany; Other Family Members; China; and Addition.
Arrangement of the Papers
The collection is arranged in eight series:
Correspondence with Poets, 1899-1943
Correspondence with Authors, Artists, Musicians, and Actors, 1886-1947
General File, 1836-1941
Family Correspondence,1883-1941
Miscellany, 1892-1939
Other Family Members, 1896-1941
China, 1921-1941
Addition, 1931
Container List
- Correspondence with Poets, 1899-1943 (Box 1-14)
  Correspondence between Chase and American and English poets.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent. Containers 12-14 at the end of the file consist of material relating to poets and poetry.
  - Abercrombie, Lascelles, 1916-1917 (Box 1)
  - Aiken, Conrad, 1921-1930
  - Alderson, Althea, 1934
  - Aldington, Richard and Mrs. Richard, 1917
  - Aldis, Dorothy, manuscript verse, undated
  - Alford, John, 1918
  - Allen, Bertha, 1919-1923
  - Armstrong, Martin, 1921-1922
  - Arnold, F. W., 1932-1937
  - Arnold, Winnifred, 1919
  - Asquith, Herbert A., 1918
  - Auslander, Joseph, 1938
  - Ayscough, Florence, 1922-1935
  - Bantock, Raymond, 1925-1926
  - Barber, C. M., poem and letter, undated
  - Baring, 1917
  - Bates, Katherine Lee, 1914-1915
  - Behenna, K. A., 1918-1924
  - Bellinger, Martha (Mrs. Franz), 1917-1925
  - Belloc, Hillaire, 1917-1924
  - Benet, Stephen Vincent, 1926
  - Benet, William Rose, 1917-1926
  - Bennett, Dorothy Graham (Mrs. James W.), 1925-1933
  - Benson, Arthur Christopher, 1918
  - Berry, A. L., 1932
  - Billie, Anna M., 1925-1926
  - Binns, Henry Bryan, 1917-1929
  - Binyon, Lawrence, 1907-1926
  - Blunden, Edmund, 1921-1930
  - Blunt, Wilfred Scarven, 1922
  - Bottomley, Gordon, 1916-1917 (Box 2)
  - Bradford, E. E., 1922-1923
  - Brockington, Allen, 1925
  - Bridges, Robert, 1917
  - Brooks, Charles Stephen, 1919-1929
  - Buchau, John, 1921
  - Butterfield, Frances Westgate, 1924-1941
  - Burgess, Stella, 1924-1928
  - Bynner, Witter, 1918-1931
  - Campbell, Joseph, 1917-1926
  - Cane, Melville H., 1930
  - Cannan, Gilbert, 1918
  - Cannan, Mary Wedderburn, 1929-1931
  - Carpenter, Edward, 1918
  - Cather, Willa, 1922-33
  - Cave, Angela, 1931
  - Chaple, P. W., 1912-1915
  - Chesterton, G. K., 1909-1927
  - Christman, W. W., 1928
  - Clark, Philip, 1926
  - Clarke, Austin, circa 1928
  - Clutton-Breck, Arthur, undated
  - Coburn, W. J., 1913-1918
  - Couldrey, Oswald, 1922 (Box 3)
  - Cousins, James H., 1917-1923
  - Coutts, Francis (Lord Latymer), 1927
  - Crapsey, Adelaide, 1919-1931
  - Creston, Dormer, 1920
  - Crosland, T. W. H., 1918
  - Cross, Norman, 1927
  - Crowley, Aleister, 1918
  - Davidson, Gustav, 1938-1939
  - Davies, William H., 1917-1930
  - Dawson, W., undated
  - De la Mare, Walter, 1916-1934
  - Dell, Floyd, undated
  - Desborough, Lord (re Julian D.S.O.), 1918
  - Dilke, 1918
  - Dobson, Austin, 1917
  - Doolittle, H. D. (Hilda), 1922-1930
  - Doughty, Charles Montague, 1918
  - Douglas, Lord Alfred, 1918
  - Dowden, Edward, 1911
  - Draper, Jessamine K. (Mrs. Edward), undated
  - Duncan, Winifred (Mrs. William) (also Mrs. Francis Winifred Sutcliffe Greaves), 1911-1927
  - Dunsany, Lord
    - Correspondence, 1916-1917
    - Wax seals, 1917
  - Eaton, Howard, 1917-1918
  - Edson, P. J., 1927-1928 (Box 4)
  - Edwards, Harry Stillwell, 1930-1933
  - Eliot, T. S., 1922
  - Ellis, Havelock, 1925-1926
  - Ellis, Edith M. O. (Mrs. Havelock), 1911-1917
  - Ellis, Mildred, 1918-1919
  - Ensor, R. C. K., 1917
  - Erskine, John, 1905-1908
  - Fisher, A. Hugh
    - Correspondence and poems, 1911-1929
    - Manuscripts of published and unpublished poems with margin notes of dates of publication
    - Copies of Library of Congress letters, 1912-1933
    - Newspaper and magazine articles, 1905-1934
    - Miscellaneous Fisherina, 1901-1913
    - Clippings of Chase lectures on Fisher
  - Fisher, Mrs. A. Hugh, 1911-1914
  - Flanner, Hildegarde, 1926
  - Flecker, Helle (Mrs. James Elroy), 1917-1930
  - Fletcher, John Gould, 1918-1930 (Box 5)
  - Ford, Madox Ford (Hueffer), 1911-1913
  - Fox, Moireen, 1917
  - Frank, Marim G., 1925-1926
  - Freeman, John, 1916-1926
  - Frost, Elizabeth H., 1928
  - Frost, Robert Lee, 1917-1930
  - Le Galliene, Richard, 1934
  - Gale, Norman, 1917-1926
  - Galesworthy, John, 1917
  - Gammons, Harold W., 1932
  - Garrard, Lindsay, 1927-1928
  - Gerry, W. H., 1931-1932
  - Gibbon, Monk, 1927-1936
  - Gibson, Wilfrid Wilson, 1916-1930
  - Gillette, Charles L., 1926-1927
  - Gogarty, Oliver St. John, 1927
  - Gore-Booth, Eva, 1917
  - Gosse, Sir Edmund, 1910-1931 (Box 6)
  - Gorell, 1928
  - Grantham, A. E., 1922
  - Gray, G. Douglas, 1925
  - Graves, Robert, 1918-1930
  - Green, A. Romney, 1913-1916
  - Griffiths, E. Maude, 1923-1924
  - Guest, Flora Bigelow, 1919
  - Hall, James Norman, 1918-1919
  - Hamilton, George Rostrover, 1929
  - Harding, H. I., 1922
  - Hardy, Thomas
    - News clippings and criticism, 1911-1941
    - Personal correspondence, 1911-1917
  - Harvey, Lieutenant F. W., 1917
  - Haugh, Irene, 1929
  - Henderson, Ruth Evelyn, 1938-1943
  - Hepburn, Elizabeth Newport, 1936
  - Hewes, Charles Edwin, 1932-1934
  - Hewlett, Maurice, 1917-1924
  - Hinkson, Katherine Tynan, 1917
  - Hodgson, Ralph
    - Manuscript of poem, "The Bride," 1942
    - Miscellany, 1914-1930
  - Holmes, Edmond, 1923
  - Horton, George, 1931
  - Horton, Marion Robbines, poems, undated
  - Housman, A. E., 1918-1930
  - Housman, Lawrence, 1917
  - Huntington, Archer Milton, 1904-1935
  - Huntington, Helen (Mrs. Granville Barker), 1899-1907
  - Hu Shih, [card], undated
  - Jeffers, Uma (Mrs. Robinson), 1927
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood, 1905-1928
  - Joyce, James, 1918-1922
  - Judd, George Element, 1934-38
  - Kaufman, Herbert, 1918 (Box 7)
  - Kehoe, Mary Jane, 1932
  - Kilmer, Joyce, 1917-1919
  - Kipling, Rudyard, 1917-1935
  - Kirby, Elizabeth, 1917
  - Koopman, Harry Lyman, 1933
  - Lauru, Juliet Bredon, article and correspondence, undated
  - Lawrence, D. H., 1916
  - Ledoux, Louis Vernon, 1905-1939
  - Lee, Alan W. Simms, 1926
  - Ledwidge, Francis, 1916-1917
  - Leonard, William Ellery, 1917-1936
  - Leslie, Shane, 1918
  - Lindsay, Vachel, 1915-1930
  - Linn, Edith Lenore Willis, 1918
  - Lowell, Amy, 1917-1922
  - Lunt, Carroll, 1923-1924
  - Macaulay, Rose, 1917
  - Mackail, J. W., 1910-1917
  - Mackail, Margaret (Mrs. J.W.) and Clare (daughter), 1910-1913
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1936-1939
  - Maddox, Emily, 1935
  - Magill, Patrick, 1918
  - Markham, A. C. (Mrs. Edwin M.), 1928
  - Marsh, Sir Edward, 1917-1919
  - Marvin, Burdette K., 1926
  - Martin, E. M., 1922-1923
  - Masefield, John, 1916-1930
  - Masters, Edgar Lee, 1917-1926
  - Matheson, Anne Nancy, 1910-1917 (Box 8)
  - Merchant, Frank, 1936-1937
  - Meyerstein, E. W. H., 1932-1933
  - Meynell, Alice, 1914-1917
  - Meynell, Alice and W. M., children of: sons, Francis and Everard; and daughters, Olivia and Grazia, 1915-1917
  - Meynell, Wilfrid, 1915-1922
  - Mew, Charlotte, 1918
  - Miles, Susan Ursula Roberts, 1920-1922
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent [Lewis Chase letters only], 1922-1930
  - Milliken, Margaret B., 1932
  - Mitchell, Susan L., 1917
  - Moore, T. Sturge, 1917
  - Monro, Harold, 1916-1930
  - Morris, May (daughter of William Morris), 1912-1918
  - Moran, Irene Shirley (Mrs. Edward), 1933-1936
  - Morsell, Mary P., 1917
  - Muir, Edwin, 1929
  - Mukerji, Dhan Gopal, 1919-1920
  - Mullins, J. Faithe, 1923-1925
  - Murphy, Ethel Allen, 1907-1910
  - Murphy, J. Lee, 1932-1933
  - Murray, T. C. 1928
  - Murray, John Middleton, 1921-1928
  - Naidu, Madame Saroniji, 1917
  - Neidig, William J., 1917
  - Newbolt, Sir Henry, 1916-1917
  - Nichols, Robert, 1917-1926 (Box 9)
  - Noguchi, Yone, 1920-1921
  - Noyes, Alfred, 1917-1930
  - O'Conner, Frank, 1927
  - Ogilvie, Juliet, 1923-1924
  - O'Neill, Eugene, 1929-1934
  - O'Sullivan, Seumas, 1917-1929
  - Owen, C. Everard, 1916-1917
  - Palmer, Henry Robinson, 1932-1934
  - Patton, Marion Keep (Mrs. Waldron Webb), 1916-1922
  - Peck, Elizabeth, 1936-1938
  - Pound, Ezra, 1922-1930
  - Presland, John (Gladys Skelton), 1917
  - Pulese, M., undated
  - Prior, G., 1911-1914
  - Punnett, Edith A., 1925
  - Putnam, Caroline, 1904-1906
  - Rankin, Marjorie, poetry, undated
  - Ray, Walter, 1919-1922
  - Rhys., Ernest, 1916-1917
  - Rice, Cale Young, 1910-1921
  - Roberts, Sir Charles George Douglas, 1913
  - Roberts, W. H., 1927
  - Robinson, E. A., 1917-1940
  - Rodken, John, undated
  - Romanes, Norman, 1917
  - Ross, Ronald, undated
  - Rossetti, W. M., undated
  - Rowe, Dorothy, poetry and note, undated
  - Russell, George William ("A.E.") (Box 10)
    - 1917-1935
    - Drawings, 1935
  - Russell, Irene Freda, 1918
  - Sabin, A. K., 1917
  - Saintsbury, George E. B., 1910-1911
  - Sandburg, Carl, 1917
  - Sargant, Edmund Beale, 1916-1917
  - Sassoon, Seigfried, 1918-1930
  - Schauffler, Goodrich Capen, poems and note, undated
  - Scott, Winfield W., 1932-1935
  - Scruggs, Anderson, 1935-1939
  - Seaman, Sir Owen, 1918
  - Searight, Jeanette, 1924
  - Shanks, Edward, 1917
  - Shakespeare, John Howard (for son Captain William G.0, 1917
  - Shea, Michael F., 1932
  - Sidgwick, Frank, 1926-1927
  - Sitwell, Edith, 1922
  - Smith, C. Fox, 1917
  - Snell, George, poem and article, undated
  - Snow, Wilbert, 1929
  - Sorley, W. R., 1920
  - Spearing, Edna Mead, 1926
  - Spicer, Elizabeth, 1936
  - Spingarn, J. E., 1903-1935
  - Squire, J. C., 1918-1921
  - Squire, Phyrne, 1932-1937
  - Starbuck, Victor, 1935
  - Stephens, James, 1916-1930
  - Stocker, Helen, 1923
  - Strauss, Samuel Wolfe, 1940
  - Stuart, Muriel, 1921-1922
  - Tai Jen, original poem and translations, undated (Box 11)
  - Tennant, E. Wyndham, 1918
  - Tennent, Margaret S., 1918
  - Tenney, Ruth, manuscript verses, undated
  - Thompson, Edward, 1926-1928
  - Towne, Charles Hanson, 1917
  - Torbert, Alice (Mrs. Horace G.), 1938-1941
  - Trench, Herbert, 1917
  - Trevelyan, Robert Calverly, 1916-1917
  - Turner, W. J., 1917-1930
  - Untermeyer, Louis, 1917
  - Van Doren, Mark, 1925-1933
  - Van Dyke, Henry, 1909
  - Van Sittart, Sir Robert, 1925
  - Ward, Lydia Avery Coonley, 1918-1923
  - Wallace, Edna Kingsley, manuscript verse, signed and unsigned, undated
  - Warren, Sir Herbert, undated
  - Watson, Mrs. H., undated.
  - Watson, Sir William, 1917
  - Weaving, Willoughby, 1922
  - Wheelwright, John 1936
  - Whiteside, Mary Brent and Oscar Williams, 1935-1938
  - Williams, Charles, 1931-1935
  - Wimsatt, Genevieve, 1931-1941
  - Woods, Margaret L., 1917
  - Yeats, William Butler, 1917-1930
  - Young, A. J., 1927
  - Young, Ella, 1917-1928
  - Poets letters to Lewis Chase (list loaned to University of Rochester and returned to Emma Chase in May 1939) (Box 12)
  - Poets in our files, list, undated
  - Library of Congress [?] (form letter[?]), 1925
  - Poets to see abroad, list, undated
  - Pictures of poets, 1923-1926
  - "Is Poetry Worth While?", undated
  - "What is poetry?," undated
  - Christ in modern poetry, 1916, 1924-1937
  - "Studies in Single Poems," undated
  - "How They Hated Poetry," Literary Supplement, London Times, 1927, undated
  - Modern American Poetry, 1920
  - "The Liberation of American Literature," Literary Supplement, London Times, 1933
  - Poets of the sea, 1936
  - Metaphysical poetry, 1904-1905, 1937-1940
  - Poets, birthdays, 1924-1925
  - Poetry: revelation of reality, undated
  - Poetry journal, undated
  - Poetry and music, 1904-1905
  - Court poets (to 1660), undated
  - "The Challenge to Poetry", 1923
  - Poetry for children, 1919-1928
  - "Experiments in Poetry," 1919
  - "The Future of Poetry," 1925
  - Oriental Poetry, 1916, 1926-1927
  - Poetry by Walt Mason (Adams Newspaper Service), 1914
  - Poets addresses, undated
  - Pastoral poetry, 1935-1938, undated
  - "Peace on Earth and Good Will, in Poetry", 1925
  - Poems in brown envelopes, undated
  - Poems: lists of copies and groups, undated
  - Lists of poets to write to, 1925-1928
  - Two articles: "A New Poetics" and "What Women Are Doing", 1925, undated
  - "Pure Poetry," 1928
  - Poetry
    - Miscellaneous news articles, 1912-1939
    - General news articles, 1917, 1929-1941 (Box 13)
  - War poetry, 1940-1941
  - Poets letters, 1935-1936
  - Metrics, 1906
  - Metre, 1924
  - Eighteenth-century verse, 1923-1924
  - Nursery Rhymes, 1926
  - Modern American Poetry, 1929
  - Lewis Chase class notes on contemporary poetry, 1926-1927
  - Poetry prize, American Association of University Women, 1933-1939
  - Clippings of poets, Chase readings, 1922-1928
  - Poetry readings by Lewis Chase, news clippings, 1923, undated
  - Modern poetry, clippings, 1931-1933
  - The sonnet, 1901, 1907, 1926, 1933-1938, undated
  - Lyric, 1902-1904, undated, (4 folders)
  - Robert Hillyer's lectures of modern poetry, 1936
  - University of Wisconsin, contemporary poets, stenographic notes, 1917
  - Poetry, 1931 (Box 14)
  - "Poetry," clippings, 1934
  - Modern poetic drama, 1934
  - Contemporary poets and poetry (Wisconsin), 1917
  - Contemporary articles on poets and poetry, 1915-1931
  - Poetry Bookshop, 1914-1919
  - Poet's early environment, undated
  - Contemporary poetry, 1927, undated
  - Poets today, bibliography, etc., 1933-1936
  - New poets, American and British, A-Z, 1914, 1922-1941
  - Emerson, compensation, 1906-1911
- Correspondence with Authors, Artists, Musicians, and Actors, 1886-1947 (Box 15-33)
  Letters to and others in literature and the arts.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Adams, Henry W., 1931 (Box 15)
  - Adams, John Stokes, 1930
  - Adams, Raymond, 1931-1932
  - Addams, Jane, 1923
  - Aitken, W. Francis, 1912-1914
  - Albright, Victor E., 1908
  - Alderman, Edwin A., 1902
  - Allan, P. B. M., 1927-1928
  - Alsop, John, 1912
  - Anderson, Charles, 1931-1935
  - Anderson, G. Oliver, 1914
  - Anderson, J. D., 1913-1914
  - Anderson, Mary, 1914
  - Anderson, Sherwood, 1922
  - Andrews, H. V., 1903-1914, 1925-1927
  - Angell, Norman, 1917
  - Appy, Henri, 1892, 1903
  - Archer, Sir William, 1915
  - Arnold, Adelaide and Julean, 1924-1928
  - Atherton, Gertrude, 1911-1913
  - Atwood, Albert, 1926-1936, undated
  - Baerlein, Henry, 1913-1914, undated
  - Baker, Franklin, 1907
  - Baker, La Reine Helen, 1910-1911
  - Baker, George P., 1928
  - Banks, Elizabeth, 1912-1914
  - Barckhausen, Henri Auguste, 1910-1911
  - Barnett, Evelyn Snead, 1908-1915, undated
  - Beard, Charles A., 1923
  - Bell, Edward Price, and Mary Mills, 1911-1913, undated (Box 16)
  - Bell, Mackenzie, 1911-1912
  - Bell, Nancy, 1914
  - Bennett, James W., 1924, undated
  - Benoit, N. and Camille, 1910-1914
  - Bersenbrugge, William, 1937-1940
  - Best, Mollie, 1914
  - Beyer, Thomas Percival, 1925-1926
  - Bishop, William Henry, 1908-1914
  - Blackburn, William Maxwell, 1931-1933, undated
  - Blankenhorn, Heber, 1927
  - Blum, Jean, 1909-1914
  - Bohn, William Edward, 1908
  - Bourgeois, Maurice, 1913
  - Bowden-Smith, A. G., 1923, 1929
  - Bowen, Mary, 1898
  - Bowerman, George F., 1929-1936
  - Bradley, William, 1904-1912
  - Brandl, von Alois, 1902-1905, undated
  - Le Braz, Anatole, 1913-1915
  - Briggs, W. D., 1914
  - Brooks, A. M., 1907-1914 (Box 17)
  - Brooks, C. Harry, 1924
  - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1933
  - Brown, Roscoe, 1905
  - Browne, Waldo R., 1912, 1918-1925, 1936
  - Bruce, J. Douglas, 1918
  - Bruce, Philip Alexander, 1914
  - Brunel, Adrian, 1913
  - Bryson, Lyman, 1926-1927
  - Buckton, Eveleen, 1912-1914
  - Burne-Jones, Philip, 1914
  - Burnette, O. Compton, 1912-1913
  - Burrows, Harold, 1924
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1898
  - Cairns, William B, 1929-1932
  - Calhoun, Lucy, undated
  - Cambiare, C. P., 1928-1929
  - Campbell, Charles, D., 1933, undated
  - Campbell, Lily B., undated
  - Campbell, Killis, 1914-1934
  - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1925
  - Carroll, Ed, 1929-1931
  - Carroll, E. Malcolm, 1930-1932
  - Cary, Elizabeth, 1907-1911
  - Castle, Tom, 1925
  - Cestre, Charles, 1908-1912, 1933-1936
  - Chandler, Frank, 1903-1908, 1926, 1934
  - Charles, Fred, 1907
  - Chartres, Annie V., 1912
  - Chiang, Mayling, 1936-1937
  - Chilton, Carroll Brent, 1910-1914, 1936
  - Clark, Grover, 1925 (Box 18)
  - Clarke, Creston, 1895-1897, 1936
  - Clergue, Helen, 1911
  - Clover, S. T., 1925
  - Cobb, S., 1935
  - Coburn, Charles, 1914, 1938-1940
  - Coe, George, undated
  - Coffin, Charles H., 1902
  - Coleman, Loyd R., 1925, 1933-1935
  - Collier, W. T., 1923
  - Conant, Martha P., 1911
  - Coolidge, Herbert, 1928
  - Copeland, Charles Townsend, 1937
  - Councilman, William T., undated
  - Coykendall, Frederick, 1935
  - Couling, Margaret, 1927-1940
  - Crothers, Samuel M., 1904
  - Crow, Mr. and Mrs. Carl, 1922
  - Cunliffe, John W., 1908-1911
  - Damon, Lindsay Todd, 1931-1935
  - Danton, George H., 1912-1924, 1935
  - Davis, John, 1898
  - Dawson, Arthur H., 1912
  - Day, Frank, 1928-1930
  - De Bruce, Robert, 1910-1915
  - De la Hunt, Thomas James, 1908-1914
  - De Morgan, William, 1911-1914
  - Dexter, Byron, 1926-1927
  - Dhalla, Manekji, 1915
  - Dietz, Frederick Charles, 1911-1916
  - Draper, Warwick H., 1910-1916 (Box 19)
  - Drennan, Max, 1923
  - Driesch, Hans, 1923-1930
  - Drucker, Amy, 1912-1914, (3 folders)
  - Dulac, Albert, 1913-1924
  - Dutcher, George, 1921-1926
  - Edman, Irwin and Doris Estcourt, 1927, undated
  - Evans, Lawton B., 1933
  - Faremont, Marquis, 1934-1935
  - Farrand, Max, 1929, undated
  - Faure, Emmanuel, 1909-1913
  - Ferguson, John Calvin, undated (Box 20)
  - Feuillerat, Albert, 1914-1916
  - Field, Charles K., 1897-1900, 1936, undated
  - Field, Rachel, 1935
  - Fifield, Arthur Charles, 1914
  - Filippi, Louis, 1910-1912
  - Firkins, O. W., 1912
  - Firth, C. H., 1904
  - Foot, Constance M., 1910-1914, undated
  - Foresteine, A., 1911
  - Forster, E. M., 1927-1929
  - Fournier, Paul, 1909-1912, undated
  - Fowler, John A., 1921
  - Fulton, George H., 1923-1927
  - Garrison, Wendell P., 1905-1906
  - Geniaux, Charles, 1912-1913
  - Germuin, Andre, 1911-1912
  - Giffard, Alfred, 1923-1926
  - Gilbert, Alan H., 1930-1931
  - Gilbert, Prentiss, 1919, 1931
  - Godbey, Allen H., 1930
  - Gollancz, Sir Israel, 1912-1914, 1929
  - Gostling, Frances M., 1913
  - Graham, Frank P., 1935
  - Graham, Stephen, 1926
  - Graves, F. R., 1923
  - Gray, Henry David, 1900-1916
  - Greenslet, Ferris, 1901-1915, 1922-1936, undated
  - Grierson, Francis, 1911-1913, undated
  - Grierson, H. J. C., 1923
  - Grover, Edwin Osgood, 1933
  - Hackett, Francis, 1919 (Box 21)
  - Haliburton, Richard, 1927
  - Hamilton, Clayton, 1923-1928
  - Hamon, Augustus, 1909-1911
  - Hammay, James Owen, undated
  - Hampton, Edward, 1926
  - Hanson, James H., 1886
  - Harada, Jiro, 1936
  - Harcourt, Alfred, 1925-1927
  - Harrington, Arthur H., 1932-1938, 1947
  - Harrison, John S., 1903-1915, 1925-1926, 1936
  - Hart, Henry H., 1933
  - Haultain, Arnold, 1915-1916
  - Hathaway, C. M., 1927
  - Heathcote, Dudley Petano, 1911
  - Hedges, Frank H., 1925
  - Henderson, Archibald, 1931
  - Herbert, Agnes, 1913
  - Herrick, A. G. and Raymond, 1929-1931
  - Hibbard, Addison and Frank S. Hickman, 1930-1933
  - Hill, David Jayne, 1908